CHANDAN GR

REACT JS DEVELOPER

LINKEDIN GITHUB

Contact: 9945622234

Email: chandan2809gr@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Highly skilled software development professional bringing 4 years of experience in on React js developer (3 years on MERN), Also expertise at software design, development, monitoring of web applications. Also experienced at technical leadership, handling a small team. Experienced in full project life cycle from design to product release. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EXPERIENCE

React is developer

Gocool Inc -2 year (Client- SwitchOn & HCL) | 2020- ongoing

- Implemented and worked on many features on one of the Microsoft projects.
- Introduced and implemented design software skills to assist with **improving the** project performance.
- Tested and accurately configured software and maintained high functioning hardware
- Implemented Real time Dashboards and pages using React and Node js (MERN).
 Worked on PWA, Chart.js, d3.js, Material UI and created HTML Templates.
- Have knowledge on Docker, AWS, Jenkins, WireFrames (figma).
- Worked on real time applications using sockets.
- Worked on MongoDB and message queues such as rabbitMQ and chain streams.
- Experience in handling a small team (4 members) and managing complete full project life cycle.
- Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements, reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

(MERN) Full stack developer

Eqtribe - 1 year (Client - ZestMoney) | 2019 - 2020

- Designed, Implemented real-time dashboards, charts (d3 js), and form pages using react js.
- Proficient in working as application developer involving software development, debugging, performance bench marking, and monitored web pages.
- Implemented authentication using JWT with Nodejs and Express.
- Designed and implemented payment pages for the customers.
- Developed Web Application using lasted React.js features like hooks, context API, ant-design, PWA.

Software Developer

Manhattan Associates - 1 year | 2018 - 2019

- Developed and implemented software solutions based on client requirements
- · Tested and refined software prior to rollout
- Designed and implemented real time Dashboards using React.js
- Implemented authentication using JWT with Node.js and Mongo.
- Created, delivered and maintained scalable code and worked on many HTML templates

SKILLS

React	• •	• •	
Node	• •	• •	
Mongo DB	• •	• •	
HTML CSS	• •	• •	
Redux	• •		
Docker	• •		
Sockets	• •		
RabbitMQ	• •	• •	
AWS GCP	• •		
Linux	• •		
Javascript	• •	• •	

EDUCATION

Bachelor of engineering BNMIT 2014 - 2018

PUC

JAIN College 2012 - 2014